

## INFO



#### **Phone** +8801941-222444



#### E-mail yamin.diu@gmail.com

#### **Address**



Flat B5, 18/6 Tallabag, Sobahanbag, Dhaka 1207, Bangladesh



yamin@engineer.com

## EDUCATION

**B.Sc. in CSE** 

(Computer Science Engineering) **Daffodil International University CG**PA 3.60 (out of 4) UGC Year- 2010

**Higher Secondary Certificate** Govt. Yasin College, Faridpur

GPA 3.50 (out of 5) under Dhaka Board Year- 2005

**Secondary School Certificate** Maizuddin High School, Faridpur.

GPA 2.69 (out of 5) under Dhaka Board Year- 2003

#### LANGUAGE

English Hindi Bangla

# Mohammad Bin Yamin

"I have a dream to gain the freedom to help people Through new products, helping then grow through experiences and achieving their dreams and their freedom."

#### CAREER OBJECTIVE

I am positive minded, confident and a self-reliant person. I am very hopeful and I believe that I can go through hard situations with a smile in my face. I am loyal to the people for and with whom I worked. Also I am always prefer to give my 100%.

#### **PROFILE**

A professional in Telecom and Digital payment gateway market with excellent skilled in marketing, policies, negotiations, complex analysis and strategic planning, merged with sales experience in international business. I am a very ambitious person with great learning agility and good business acumen and can be able to take many challenges of helping to grow a start-up telecom and digital payment gateway company. Has excellent ability to gain new customers through business development techniques, and having keen understanding of customer issues.

#### EXPERIENCE

O 2015 - Present Assistant Manager , Songbird Telecom Limited ( Sister concern of Reve System and Agni System )

> As Carrier Relations Manager you will be leading market analytics, business performance analysis & reporting and budget planning & forecasting for the International Wholesale Voice and SMS A2P/P2P business.

2013 - 2015

Assistant Manager, Songbird Telecom Limited

As Carrier Relations Manager you will be leading market analytics, business performance analysis & reporting and budget planning & forecasting for the International Wholesale Voice business.

2010 - 2013

Apple Certified Macintosh Technician (ACMT), **Executive Machines Ltd** 

I am install, configure, and fix macOS and interact with their users and guide them on queries and issues related to hardware and software. Professionals configure, install, and maintain Mac systems, their peripherals, and mobile

**2009 - 2010** 

**IT Officer, Intraco Group** 

As an IT technical support officer, I am install and configure computer systems, diagnose hardware and software faults and solve to the technical and application problems, either over the phone or in person .

## EXPERTISE

Working Knowledge



Computer Aided Software Engineering •••••

Problem Solving

 $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\bullet$ 

Creative

ullet

Ability to Develop



## SKILLS

Communication & Interpersonal

Collaboration

Negotiation & Persuasion

Project Management

Research & Strategy

Computer Skills

Business Intelligence

Sales Management

Marketing

HOBBIES











## INTERESTS

**Travel** 

**Playing Music** 

Reading

Coffee

Pets

Gaming

**Outdoors** 

#### PERSONAL INFORMATION

Name : Mohammad Bin Yamin.

Father's Name : A.N.M. Aminul Islam.

Mother's Name : Mosammat Rehana Amin.

Date of Birth : 1st December 1988.

Religion : Islam (Sunni).

**Marital Status** : Married.

**Nationality** : Bangladeshi.

**National ID** : 2693624790836

#### INTERNATIONAL CARRIER LITERACY

- Establishing the Bilateral & Wholesale voice business.
- Responsible for generating business through mutual exchange of traffics.
- Responsible for deal and accomplish it successfully.
- Responsible for payment come in due date.
- Client and Vendor creating.
- Capable to handle customer queries/complains instantly.
- Strong interpersonal and communication skills.
- Positive attitude and self-motivated with clients and Vendor.

#### TELECOMMUNICATION LITERACY

- Monitoring the Network Alarms in NOC or OMC.
- Configuration of BTS and MW in NOC/OMC.
- Generating reports of alarms and network performance.
- Setup Switch Server.
- Addition/ deletion of hardware configurations from NOC/OMC.
- Uploading of new SW of network elements from NOC/OMC

#### SKILLS

Any Software Operating IT Troubleshooting Any Operating System Operated Adobe Photoshop Adobe InDesign Microsoft Word Microsoft PowerPoint Microsoft Excel

#### REFERENCES



MD . Tanzirul Hasan Bhuiyan Head of Sales, Unit 3 The City Bank Limited Kha 199/3, Progati Sarani, Middle Badda, Dhaka 1212 Cell: +8801914-444590

Phone: 02-55055128 Ext. 111

Email:

tanzirul\_hasan@thecitybank.com



Md. Torikul Hasan Bhuiyan **Head of Sales & Communication BCL Fluid System** 28/B, 29/A, Kakril VIP Road, Dhaka, Bangladesh. Mobile: +8801708-450271 Mobile: +8801711-848368

SOCIAL MEDIA

Email: tusar@foras-bcl.com



Yamin.Diu



Yamin.Diu



Yamin.Diu

#### COMPUTER LITERACY

I am familiar with MAC and Windows operating system along with

- Apple Macintosh Program.
- Microsoft Program, Microsoft Office Package.
- Setup Web Server.
- Networking.
- Internet Operating.
- Java Programming Language.
- Database Manipulation & Maintenance (SQL Server 2000).

#### HARDWARE KNOWLEDGE

- Installation of PC-Hardware Device For Mac and windows.
- Hard Drive Partition & Format For Mac and windows.
- Operating System Installation & Maintenance in Mac & windows.
- PC Troubleshooting Mac and windows.

#### SECURITY CLEARANCE

I have no criminal records at any court record or at any police station in Bangladesh.

Specimen Signature

Mohammad Yamin

(Mohammad Bin Yamin)